ImPOS

Cover Letter

Dale Salter

October 29, 2014

Dear Sean O'Meara,

I am writing to express interested in working for your company over my summer break (December - March) as an Software Developer which is part of an internship.

ImPOS particularly interested me because of one of the job ads you posted on Seek sometime ago, it mentioned what your team was like to work with and the technologies that you were using. After speaking further to Carissa Babb at Geared Asset Finance, I was really impressed by what she said about your team - thinking I would fit in perfectly and as I result I could not help but put forward my resumè.

One of the other reasons I would like an internship at ImPOS is solve real world problems whilst using version control, automated builds/testing, etc,. I believe am not sufficiently exposed to these at University and would like to use them on a much larger, professional scale.

I have had a great deal of experience with programming in a wide variety of languages from both University and personal interest. These range from shell scripting to mobile development.

I believe I would be an asset to your team because of my enthusiasm, drive and general love for solving problems.

In support of my application I have attached a resume providing a more detailed summary of my relevant experiences. I look forward to discussing my application further an at interview.

Yours Faithfully

Dale Salter



contact

89 Bourke St Bulleen, Vic 3105 Australia

+61 499 647 799

dalejsalter@outlook.com github.com/Compulsed

programming

▼ JavaScript C++, Java, EmberJS, NodeJS CSS3 & HTML5 adaptive, passionate, quick learner, sociable, hobbyist programmer

projects

I have completed various projects during my time at highschool and university, because either I wanted to learn a programming langauge in the context of a project or for the simple enjoyment of writing programs.

- TrendChattr: EmberJS, jQuery, Socket.IO, Bootstrap, Redis, MongoDB, TwitterAPI, Git A startup idea my friend and I had, for a mainstream chat room client, a more polished and accessible version of IRC. Uses a transient data model which pushes to all Socket.IO connections, the chat rooms are based off of the trending topics on Twitter.

 View TrendChatt
- **GymTracker:** PHP, MySQL, CSS3, HTML5, jQuery, AJAX Tracks user progress, tells the lifter when they are plateauing, draws progress graphs.
- MovieThoughts: NodeJS, EJS, MySQL, AJAX, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap Stores my thoughts and theories on my movie catalog, pulls data from IMDB's API.

I have done plenty more projects, some involve **multithreading**, **math**, **serialization**, **data structures**.

Some of which are located here, GitHub

programming

Years: 4+ C++, JavaScript, Bash

Years: 3+ Pascal, C, HTML, CSS, MySQL, PHP, jQuery

Years: 2+ EJS, Java, Android, NodeJS

Recent: Python, LaTeX, Prolog, JavaCC, Play Framework, EmberJS, Socket.IO, Golang, VHDL,

MongoDB, Redis

Tools: IntelliJ, Visual Studios, Xcode, Sublime Text, Vim, Git, Maven

participation

2012-Now Developer Meet Up Groups Melbourne, Victoria

Regular attendance to various meet up groups, including Golong, Alt.net, Post-

greSQL, etc,.

2011 **Melbourne Hackerspace** Glenferrie, Victoria

Regularly attend and help out with the hobbyist electronics meet up

awards

2011 **Excellence in Technology** Mooroolbark College, Victoria

Awarded to the best graduating student in a particular field

education

2012-Now **Bachelor** of Engineering (Software Engineering) Swinburne University, Victoria

During my time at university I have been exposed to a wide variety of technologies; from debugging VHDL to developing complex web applications. While university sparks my interests in particular technologies, the ones enjoy I con-

tinue to play with.

2005-2011

Mooroolbark College, Victoria

Specialist Mathematics, Mathematical Methods, English, Software Applications & Chemistry.

experience

2012-2013 **PC Medic**

St Kilda, Victoria

IT Technician and Sales

General systems repairs, soft and hardware upgrades, debugging & installations, use of a POS, product & service sales and used a systemic approach to general problem solving.

Transferable skills:

- Making amazing coffee
- Systemic approaches to problem solving
- Sourcing the correct information from clients & customers
- Understandings of IT in business settings

2011-2012 **Fast Business Computing**

Ringwood, Victoria

Junior Developer

General applications development, sourcing customer requirements, reading & writing documentation and managing time frames.

Transferable skills:

- Applying JavaScript to NetSuite developement
- Writing documentation for application code
- Simple agile development methodologies

interests

professional: web design, web app creation, software data structures & algorithms, multithreading, new technologies **personal:** gym, coffee, hobbyist electronics

reference

Venkata Rajesh VASA

Course Conveyor, Swinburne University

Rvasa@swin.edu.au, +61 3 9214 5011